A Finding Aid to the Robert Smithson and Nancy Holt Papers, 1905-1987, bulk 1952-1987, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1955-1985; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 5.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-11, Box 18, RD 31
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Non-Smithson Related, 1965-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in RD 31
  - Newsletter, Public News + News Network, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals, with Articles by Robert Smithson, Archival Resource Key
    - 0 to 9, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Artforum, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Art Now: New York, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Art Present, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Arts Yearbook, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Aspen, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Aspen, Oversized, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Avalanche, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Avalanche, Oversized, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Harvard Advocate, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Kalejdoskop, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - On Site, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pan, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ta', 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals, with Articles on Robert Smithson, Archival Resource Key
    - Art in America, 1976, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Art in America, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Art in America, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Art in America, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Artforum, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Artforum, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Arts, 1981; 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Arts Canada, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Interfunktionen, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Substitute, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Taide, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Printed Material, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Inventory List of Unfilmed Books and Periodicals, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Inventory List of Unfilmed Phonograph (Music) Records, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Scrapbook, 1966-1973; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 11, Box 16
  The scrapbook contains clippings of Smithson's published articles from 1966 to 1973 with annotated shorthand notes on album pages.
  The scrapbook retains its original arrangement.
  - "Robert Smithson 1938-1973, Essays, Articles, Statements", 1966-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Artwork, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Box 11
  Artwork consists of Christmas cards collaged by Smithson, and sketches by Smithson and Leo Valledor.
  The series is arranged by artwork type.
  - Artwork by Robert Smithson, Archival Resource Key
    - Christmas Card, "Christmas is for Children", circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Christmas Card, "Santa Claus vs. the Creature from the Black Lagoon", circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Sketches, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Sketches by Leo Valledor, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Photographs, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders Box 11, Box 18
  Photographic materials include prints and negatives of Smithson with friends, promotional Hollywood movie stills, copyprints of other artists' artwork, and original photographs of artwork by Rosemarie Castoro, Michael Heizer, and N.E. Thing Co.
  The series is arranged by subject.
  Series, except for duplicates, has been digitized in entirety.
  - Robert Smithson with Friends, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Robert Smithson with Friends, Oversized, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Robert Smithson with Howard Junker, New Jersey, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Promotional Movie Stills, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Works by Other Artists, Original Prints, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Works by Other Artists, Copy Prints, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Artifacts, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 11, Box 14, OV 19
  Artifacts consist of a paper bag silkscreened with a Campbell's soup can (Warhol), promotional buttons (N.E. Thing Co.), various organic materials, and two art kits. The Geometric Units for Logic Test kit consists of 17 geometric shape cutouts; the Gravity for Traveling I kit consists of over 15 samples of mixed materials, including foams, glass, fabrics, plastics, and metals.
  The series is arranged by artifact type.
  Series is partially digitized. Items in Box 14 have not been digitized.
  - Bag, Campbell's Soup Can (Andy Warhol screenprint), Oversized, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 19)
    Oversized material from Box 11, F32
  - Buttons, N.E. Thing Co., "Artoficial", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Geometric Units for Logic Test, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Gravity for Traveling I, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Framed Moths, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Rattlesnake Head, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Unidentified Amphibious Organism, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
- Nancy Holt Papers, circa 1960s-1980s; Series 13; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Box 12-13, 15, OV 27, FC 37-38
  The Nancy Holt papers consist of correspondence, a grant application, printed materials, and project files and material related to her motion picture film Pine Barrens (1975) and her seminal environmental work of art Sun Tunnels (1976). Pine Barrens original elements include a release print, outtakes, trims, and soundtrack, and paper records include footage logs and a detailed handwritten description of the film. There is a video documentary about the making of Sun Tunnels.
  The series has been arranged by material type.
  Paper-based records in this series have been digitized. Some of the film and video recordings in this series have been copied for research access and are available in the Archives of American Art offices. Much of the original film materials from the Pine Barrens and Sun Tunnels projects have been transferred to video for research access, including the Pine Barrens release print and a portion of outtakes, and the Sun Tunnels work print.
  - Correspondence, circa 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Grant Application, National Endowment for the Arts, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Collection of Exhibition Reviews, 1974-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Event Announcements, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Event Announcements, Oversized, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 27)
  - Project, Pine Barrens (1975), Archival Resource Key
    - Handwritten Description of Film, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Film Log, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Release Print, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 88)
    - Release Print, Access Copies, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Digital Betacam) duplicate; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) duplicates (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Outtakes reel 1, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 89)
    - Outtakes reel 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 90)
    - Outtakes, Access Copies, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Digital Betacam) duplicate; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) duplicates (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 1, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 91)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 92)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 3, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 93)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 4, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 94)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 5, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 95)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 6, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 96)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 7, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 97)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 8, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 98)
    - Additional Outtakes reel 9, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 99)
    - Titles (Work Print), 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 100)
    - Trims, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 37)
    - Soundtrack, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 10.5 inch diameter (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Project, Sun Tunnels (1976), Archival Resource Key
    - Clipping, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Work Print, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel original 16 mm (Item FC 38)
    - Work Print, Access Copies, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Digital Betacam) duplicate; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) duplicates (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Drawing of Ann Tobin, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Robert Smithson Personal Library, Series 14; Archival Resource Key; 48.4 Linear feet Boxes 39-87
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged as four subseries.
  14.1: Books, Not Annotated
  14.2: Books, Annotated
  14.3: Vinyl Records
  14.4: Magazines
  Series has not been digitized.
  - Books, Not Annotated, 14.1; Archival Resource Key
    - A - Benstock, Archival Resource Key (Box 39)
    - Berrill - Burroughs, Archival Resource Key (Box 40)
    - Butler - Coburn, Archival Resource Key (Box 41)
    - Cochran - Eastlake, Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
    - Eastwood - F, Archival Resource Key (Box 43)
    - G - Hammett, Archival Resource Key (Box 44)
    - Hansen - Kastor, Archival Resource Key (Box 45)
    - Kitses - Levine, Archival Resource Key (Box 46)
    - Lewis - Nabokov (The Eye), Archival Resource Key (Box 47)
    - Nabokov (Ada) - Plath, Archival Resource Key (Box 48)
    - Poe - Sa, Archival Resource Key (Box 49)
    - Sc - Sp, Archival Resource Key (Box 50)
    - Stein - V, Archival Resource Key (Box 51)
    - W - Z, Archival Resource Key (Box 52)
    - Condition Issues, Archival Resource Key (Box 53)
  - Books, Annotated, 14.2; Archival Resource Key
    - A - Burroughs, Archival Resource Key (Box 54)
    - Burton - D, Archival Resource Key (Box 55)
    - E - F, Archival Resource Key (Box 56)
    - G - Ha, Archival Resource Key (Box 57)
    - He - La, Archival Resource Key (Box 58)
    - Le - M, Archival Resource Key (Box 59)
    - N - P, Archival Resource Key (Box 60)
    - R - Sp, Archival Resource Key (Box 61)
    - St - Woolf, Archival Resource Key (Box 62)
    - Worringer - Z + Condition Issues, Archival Resource Key (Box 63)
    - Complete Series (History of England, Popular Educator), Archival Resource Key (Box 64)
    - Maps and Photographs from Library Books, Archival Resource Key (Box 65)
  - Vinyl Records, 14.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Vinyl Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 66)
    - Vinyl Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 67)
    - Vinyl Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 68)
    - Vinyl Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 69)
    - Vinyl Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 70)
  - Magazines, 14.4; Archival Resource Key
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 71)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 72)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 73)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 74)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 75)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 76)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 77)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 78)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 79)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 80)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 83)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 84)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 85)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 86)
    - Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 87)